hello everyone it is a beautiful quiet
morning over here I was in a bookish
mood as I often find myself in the
spring I love to take my books Outdoors
to share them with the wildflowers and
it occurred to me that I have the option
to make videos related to books on this
channel which is something I've done
before but I've not done a book
recommendation specific video I think so
I wanted to mix those in just now and
then if you are not a reader or
interested in books at all no worries I
will be making my more usual types of
videos I wanted to mix in these more
bookish videos simply for my own sake I
know most people will probably not be
that interested in them so no worries at
all but I did want to make this video
talking about some books that inspire me
books that either highlight daily life
in a positive way and the beauty of kind
of normal everyday things or at the very
least books that have helped me have a
new perspective on my own daily life and
hopefully some of these it might be some
that you're interested in looking into
or not I mean books are so individual
it's it's really hard to give a
recommendation and know for sure you
will connect with a book in the same way
I will some of my favorite books are
books that help me see my own daily life
all the mundane ordinary moments as
something more interesting and
meaningful that is my way to encourage
myself to always be looking at life in
new ways and keeping it interesting and
appreciating the beauty around me and so
I wanted to find books that encapsulated
those feelings for me at least however I
did want to take a moment before I start
with the books to share with you some
tips if you are someone who wants to
become a reader or is interested in
reading more but I think it is important
to appreciate whatever hobby you are
into we're all different and unique so
never feel any obligation to be be
reading or that you're failing somehow
and not reading at all however I do find
it could be helpful to get you more
passionate about reading if you develop
your philosophy behind it for example
for me reading is my way to build up my
ability to concentrate and focus on
tasks to keep a very healthy balance
between me and my phone and Technology
making sure I'm taking a break and
unplugging and doing more slower paced
activities that are more Mindful and
involve me having to build up that sense
of focus and a little bit of that
self-control over time as well and in
regards to not being able to find any
book interesting enough to finish I do
think it might be helpful to you to try
a different genre or a different type of
book or a book you wouldn't normally
expect to read it might be fiction or
non-fiction it might be a comedy book
written by a comedian you might find a
book written by a celebrity or someone
that you would Meyer and you might enjoy
their work as well in seeing their
perspective on their own life or their
work there are so many different types
of books and there's magazines and
there's web comics and there's graphic
novels all of them involve reading I
have heard that quote kind of float
around of it's all about finding the
right book I hope there's no judgment
for me starting out with this book
because it is a chapter book and it's
extremely simplistic and it is not going
to challenge your vocabulary and it is
one that you probably read when you were
maybe five years old however the Frog
and Toad treasury is an absolutely
beautiful collection of stories and frog
and toad in my opinion uh really know
how to live well they live mindfully
they live slowly they appreciate every
moment and even the smallest experiences
are Adventures for them everything from
just going to the river to take a bath
to going on a bicycle to planting a
garden all of it is so exciting and
interesting to both characters I will
mention it briefly but the World of Pooh
is an absolutely wonderful Treasury and
of course Pooh Bear is all about
elevating the ordinary things in our
lives and appreciating every little bit
especially food I think he really
appreciates food so much so if you're
interested in giving a classic book a
try this might be a good option however
I know the writing style of very old
books is not for everyone so you are
forewarned if you love poetry you might
enjoy the lost spells these are a
collection of poems and art
illustrations that are all about nature
and animals and plants and for me
because I live in a natural area it
really elevates my experience however
even if you don't live in an area with
obvious nature all around nature is
still there it is very present from the
air you breathe the wind the clouds the
trees I feel that books like these
encourage us to slow down and notice all
those beautiful things around us that
might be hard to find sometimes if you
have a tree near your house or you are
able to go somewhere where there are
trees or even just watch documentaries
about forests and trees you absolutely
need to read the hidden life of trees I
will not show this book in too much
detail because I dropped it in a mud
puddle while taking it on an adventure
and it looks very worn out the creator
of this book has such a compassionate
and beautiful approach to understanding
the forest and tree life going into
detail about tree Families how trees
communicate and connect with each other
and with us it will change your entire
perspective and it will make you feel
very connected and hopefully very
passionate about being part of the
incredible movement of preserving our
forests and wildlands for future
Generations another classic book that I
really enjoy is The Wind in the Willows
by Kenneth Graham I know because this is
a classic some of the vocabulary in it
is a little dated and that is always the
case I think with pretty much all
classics some words had completely
different meanings in the past as they
do now or they were just simply used in
different contexts and so um it's
definitely something to keep in mind
whenever you read classic books because
it is not for everyone The Wind and The
Willows tells the story of mole and
ratty and Toad and all these curious
some of them eccentric creatures that
live on a riverbank and all the
adventures they get up to some of them
quite surprisingly dangerous too mole
and ratty are enchanting characters and
I love the way they communicate there
also happens to be a free movie on
YouTube called The Wind and The Willows
I'm not sure what year it came out I
will I will put it here but it is a a
cartoon and it portrays this story in my
opinion even better than the book
version it is so delightful and funny
and cute now I do not have any of his
books written for adults but I do have
his children's treasury so I thought I
would share it it is James Harriet's
treasury for children and he also wrote
a lot of books for adults so if you're
not interested in the children's
treasury you can check out his books for
adults however the children's treasury
does have beautiful paintings in it so I
mean if you're me you would go for the
one with the paintings but that's just
my opinion James Harriet was a
veterinarian who wrote many enchanting
books about his experience working as a
vet in rural areas and he has so many
adventures and hilarious stories to tell
you are forewarned because he's a
veterinarian he does go quite into
detail about the surgeries and
procedures he has to do on pets
sometimes there are sad things that
happen but I feel that overall it is
such an incredible collection of stories
he has written that just make you want
to fall in love with the little things
and just appreciating all the little
moments in your life the audiobooks
narrated by Christopher Timothy are some
of the best narrated audiobooks I think
have ever been created so I actually
encourage you to listen to them more
than read them because I grew up
listening to those stories and they're
just so so funny and enchanting and
heartwarming this one is the penderwicks
by Jean Birdsall it is a national book
award winner it is a delightful book all
about a bunch of siblings enjoying their
summer break and all the shenanigans
they get up to and it is also
heartwarming and it is about friendship
and creating memories together as a
family The Evolution of Calpurnia Tate
does not have its dust jacket because
I'm very good at losing the dust jackets
of books so that is unfortunate but the
main character Calpurnia Tate in my
opinion is kind of a American
Reincarnation of Anne from Anne of Green
Gables and she is such a delightful
personality she is spunky and she has a
big family and she has a very a close
connection to her grandfather who shares
her interest in nature it is such an
enchanting book about showing how you
can create your own magic in your life
even when things outside of you are
limiting you in some shape or form the
Forgotten Garden by Kate Morton is just
a beautifully written kind of almost
slightly poetic book that has Intrigue
and mystery and it is a historical
fiction book as well there is a young
girl in it who has been abandoned and
she has a suitcase that has a book of
fairy tales in it and it is kind of her
only symbol that you know is able to
connect her to her past and it is a
really interesting mysterious story and
I think it is beautifully written
another children's book but that I
really think you should not Overlook is
a Jill barklam's stories I just chose
one at random I picked up the secret
staircase but um it they are absolutely
delightful stories they're very simple
stories but I think that the reason
reason I love them is because of the art
there is so much to look at in her art
and in her drawings and it is such a
visual treat the borrowers by Mary
Norton is a book that was very close to
my heart growing up even though it's
about tiny people that live in a house
and you may wonder how is that related
to elevating ordinary life but in my
opinion it made my imagination just run
wild when I was reading this book I was
imagining all sorts of possibilities of
little tiny people and fairies and
animals and all sorts of things and I
absolutely loved the experience of
reading it and it offered a new
perspective on daily life it also
inspired the Studio Ghibli movie The
Secret Life of arietti which is
enchanting and if you have not watched
it you definitely need to now this is a
fantasy book but I feel like it falls
into that category of Slice of Life
fantasy meaning that it is all about
romanticizing daily life and enjoying
the little things and that is Legends
and lattes by Travis baldry if you enjoy
fantasy stories fantasy characters if
you like DND I'm sure you will love this
book the main character is called Viv
and she's opening up the very first
coffee shop in her town and a lot of the
townspeople do not know what coffee is
and there are all sorts of characters
and Fantastical creatures that come
visit and they even hire a little mouse
to be the cook at the cafe and it is
just about the cutest little character
and he is so passionate about cooking
and it's just a very cute very feel-good
story you are never too stressed out
reading it and that's what I love in
books next to last of my recommendation
I have recommended before so I'm going
to be brief but it is the Shady Hollow
books I actually liked the first Shady
Hollow book but I really loved the
second two and there I believe is going
to be a fourth one out in November and
so I encourage you to try any book in
the series you are interested in while
there are some overarching plots you can
kind of pick up any story in the series
and still know what's going on they're
more episodic now this is a murder
mystery and it is again about talking
animals however however so much of the
book is focused on Amazing food and
exploring this beautiful little town
called Shady Hollow and all the
adventures the main characters get up to
and to be honest I feel like the murder
part of it ends up not being as
important it's more of the experience of
Shady Hollow itself it is definitely a
surprisingly low stress book and I love
the descriptions of the libraries and
coffee shops it is just enchanting the
very last book I will recommend is a
picture book and it is Journey and you
might think that I'm recommending it to
you if you have children however I am
recommending it to you whoever you are
because I think it tells a very
important story about reconnecting to
your inner child and connecting to your
inner imagination okay thank you so much
for humoring me if you have made it this
far you must be someone who likes books
I know there are a lot of adult fiction
books that are all about elevating the
ordinary things in life so I definitely
would love you to recommend those my
recommendations I I know are rather
unique a lot of them are related to
children's books or fantasy and I know
that my recommendations are a little bit
different but that is why we have room
down below for you to share yours so I
hope you enjoyed this and I'm sending
you all my love and I will be back with
my more usual content next week so I
appreciate all the support I will see
you very very soon and take care goodbye
[Music]